Guide to the Ralph E. Pickett Papers MSS.052
Fales Library and Special Collections
Ralph E. Pickett Papers
1954-1980
Fales Library and Special Collections
Pickett, Ralph E.
MSS.052
6 Linear Feet
Ralph Pickett was a professor at NYU at the School of Education, donor to the Library, and the author of numerous works of fiction, most of which remain unpublished. The papers are primarily typewritten manuscripts of Pickett's unpublished fiction.
Provenance
The papers were donated to the Fales Library by Dean Ralph Pickett in 1982.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Biographical Note
Ralph Pickett was a professor at NYU at the School of Education and a generous donor to the Bobst Library. He had established in his name a special fund for the purchase of books the library would not normally have acquired, such as the Supplementum Hellenisticum and the full set of Migne's Patrologiae Latinae. He was also the author of numerous works of fiction, most of which remain unpublished, which, as Pickett describes in a letter to Frank Walker, then librarian at Fales, "...indicate the range of my interests and foibles - campus life, oddities in the law, mystery and detective stories, historical novels, and the bizzare, outre, arcane and screwball aspects of fellow humans. Some are pretty grim; one, "The Newest Nation", is bitterly satirical. A few are placid."
Scope and Content Note
The papers are primarily typewritten manuscripts of Pickett's unpublished fiction. There are also some handwritten notes and outlines which have been interfiled with the fiction to which it refers.
Arrangement
The collection is comprised of 6 linear feet of material and is arranged into 2 series - Series I: Unpublished Manuscripts and II: Objects. The manuscripts are grouped by pseudonym and arranged alphabetically by title.
Missing Title
Series I: Unpublished Manuscripts, Originals and Carbon Copies
Series II: Sherry Glasses and Boxes
Separated Material
There is no information about materials that are associated by provenance to the described materials that have been physically separated or removed.
Manuscripts for publication.; New York (N.Y.).; Fiction |y 20th century.; New York University. School of Education; Foote, Arnold; Smith, Agatha; Tremulis, Aftron
- Series I: Unpublished Manuscripts, Originals and Carbon Copies
  Scope and Contents note
  Series 1 contains 4 boxes containing original and carbon copy typewritten manuscripts of Pickett's unpublished fiction. Pickett wrote under his own name and various pseudonyms. The manuscripts are grouped by pseudonym and arranged alphabetically by title. Series 2 contains a sherry glass box fashioned by Ralph E. Pickett.
  - Foote, Arnold. The Dorsays of New York. Chapters 1 through 6., undated; 31142040610720 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Foote, Arnold. The Dorsays of New York. Chapters 7 through 11., undated; 31142040610720 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Foote, Arnold. The Dorsays of New York. Chapters 12 through 18., undated; 31142040610720 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Foote, Arnold. The Dorsays of New York. Chapters 19 through 23., undated; 31142040610720 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Foote, Arnold. The Dorsays of New York. Chapters 24 through 27., undated; 31142040610720 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Foote, Arnold. The Dorsays of New York. Chapters 28 through 31., undated; 31142040610720 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Foote, Arnold. The Dorsays of New York. Chapters 32 through 36., undated; 31142040610720 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Adirondack Storm., undated; 31142040610720 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Anatomy of a Legacy. Chapters 1 through 3., 1966; 31142040610720 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Anatomy of a Legacy. Chapters 4 through 10., 1966; 31142040610720 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Anatomy of a Legacy. Chapters 1 through 5., 1966; 31142040610720 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Anatomy of a Legacy. Chapters 6 through 10., 1966; 31142040610720 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Anatomy of a Legacy. Chapters 6 and 7., 1966; 31142040610720 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Anatomy of a Legacy. Chapters 8 through 10., 1966; 31142040610720 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., And About Time! (two copies), 1966; 31142040610720 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., The Coincidental Murders, 1972; 31142040610720 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., The Coincidental Murders, 1972; 31142040610720 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Episodes in the Life of Debby. Chapters 1 through 7., 1958 (rev. 1979); 31142040610720 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Episodes in the Life of Debby. Chapters 8 through 11.., 1958 (rev. 1979); 31142040610720 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Episodes in the Life of Debby. Chapters 1 through 7., 1958 (rev. 1979); 31142040610720 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Episodes in the Life of Debby. Chapters 8 through 11., 1958 (rev. 1979); 31142040610720 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Family Secret., undated; 31142040610720 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Five Unsettling Tales. Stories 1 through 3., undated; 31142040610720 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Five Unsettling Tales. Stories 4 through 5., undated; 31142040610720 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Five Unsettling Tales. Stories 1., undated; 31142040610738 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Five Unsettling Tales. Stories 2 through 5., undated; 31142040610738 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Foley's Folly (two copies)., undated; 31142040610738 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., The Highboy, undated; 31142040610738 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., The Imperial Tramp, 1962 (rev. 1975); 31142040610738 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Joe Norden, 1972; 31142040610738 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Joe Norden, undated; 31142040610738 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Magna University, undated; 31142040610738 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Magna University, undated; 31142040610738 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Mr. Burnt Bones Beheaded, 1970; 31142040610738 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Mr. Burnt Bones Beheaded, 1970 (rev. 1972); 31142040610738 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., The Mystery at Wildwood., undated; 31142040610738 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Nine Short Stories Plus One Featuring Lieutenant Lorch., undated; 31142040610738 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., One Semester at Chester., undated; 31142040610738 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Pamela Spelrode in Peril., 1969 (rev. 1975); 31142040610738 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Pamela Spelrode Married., 1972 (rev. 1979); 31142040610738 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Pamela Spelrode Married., 1972 (rev. 1979); 31142040610738 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Parnassus For All., undated; 31142040610738 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Parnassus For All., undated; 31142040610738 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Professor, You Amaze Me!, 1972; 31142040610738 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Psychiatrist's Case Book. Pages 1 through 152., 1954 (rev. 1979); 31142040610746 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Psychiatrist's Case Book. Pages 153 through 291., 1954 (rev. 1979); 31142040610746 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Psychiatrist's Case Book. Pages 1 through 152., 1954 (rev. 1979); 31142040610746 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Psychiatrist's Case Book. Pages 153 through 291., 1954 (rev. 1979); 31142040610746 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Rape's Progress Book One: Flora, 1960 (rev. 1978); 31142040610746 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Rape's Progress Book One: Flora, 1960 (rev. 1978); 31142040610746 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Rape's Progress Book Two: Mandy, 1960 (rev. 1978); 31142040610746 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Rape's Progress Book Two: Mandy, 1960 (rev. 1978); 31142040610746 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Rape's Progress Book Three: Stanley, 1960 (rev. 1978); 31142040610746 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Rape's Progress Book Three: Stanley, 1960 (rev. 1978); 31142040610746 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Ride That Hobby., undated; 31142040610746 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Second Semester at Chester., 1982; 31142040610746 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Second Semester at Chester. Pages 1 through 105., 1982; 31142040610746 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Second Semester at Chester. Pages 106 through 217., 1982; 31142040610746 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., A Selection of Ten Odd Tales., undated; 31142040610746 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Shorts and Short Shorts. Part 1, undated; 31142040610746 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Shorts and Short Shorts. Part 2, undated; 31142040610746 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Tales of the Willowmere., undated; 31142040610746 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Tales of the Willowmere., undated; 31142040610746 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Tales of the Willowmere., undated; 31142040610746 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Ten Grisly Tales Plus Three., undated; 31142040610753 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Ten Grisly Tales Plus Three., undated; 31142040610753 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Terry Malwan., undated; 31142040610753 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., The Unworthy Heirs., undated; 31142040610753 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Up Where the Winds Blow. Chapters 1 through 14., 1965; 31142040610753 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Up Where the Winds Blow. Chapters 15 through 27., 1965; 31142040610753 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Up Where the Winds Blow. Chapters 28 through 33., 1965; 31142040610753 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Pickett, Ralph E., Up Where the Winds Blow. Chapters 33 through 40., 1965; 31142040610753 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Smith, Agatha. Jordan Mystery, undated; 31142040610753 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Smith, Agatha. Jordan Mystery. Copy lacks pages 1 through 12., undated; 31142040610753 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Smith, Agatha. Pushover Heaven., undated; 31142040610753 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Smith, Agatha. Pushover Heaven., undated; 31142040610753 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Smith, Agatha. Pushover Heaven. Chapters 1 through 5., undated; 31142040610753 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Smith, Agatha. Pushover Heaven. Chapters 6 through 11., undated; 31142040610753 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Tremulis, Aftron. Campus Idyll. 3 copies, 1930; 31142040610753 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Tremulis, Aftron. Murder on the Huntley Campus, 1980; 31142040610753 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Tremulis, Aftron. Scandal At Huntley 2 copies, 1980; 31142040610753 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Series II: Sherry Glasses and Boxes
  - Wooden boxes if sherry glasses. Constructed by Ralph Pickett., undated (Box 5)
  - Cardboard box, with velvet wrappings, containing 3 additional sherry glasses., undated (Box 5)